#### Contact

wardzinski.todd@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/twardzinski (LinkedIn)

www.wardzinski.info (Personal)

### Top Skills

Linux

Software Development Web Applications

### Languages

French (Limited Working) English (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** Red Hat Delivery Specialist -**Advanced Cloud Automation** CKA: Certified Kubernetes

Administrator

#### **Publications**

Development and evaluation of a tailored mHealth intervention to improve medication adherence in Blacks with uncontrolled hypertension and type 2 diabetes

Evaluation of the electronic version of the Questionnaire for Lung Transplant Patients

# Wm. Todd Wardzinski

Senior Linux Consultant at Red Hat

Manassas

# Summary

I like to do a lot with computers. My primary focus areas are in software development and Kubernetes based containerization. I have a deep seated interest in microservices extracting from the monolithic architectures of the past. My experience thus far has afforded me many different types of skills and knowledge from mobile to platform development to infra (clouds and server farms).

Application programming experience in Java, C++, C#, VB.net. Scripting experience in Bash. Mobile & Web Development (Backend / Frontend) experience in Javascript, AngularJS, Node.js, ¡Query, PHP, ASP/Razor MVC, XHTML, HTML5, XML, CSS, Cordova, iOS (Swift4), Android and Xamarin. Relational and NoSQL based databases: MySQL / MSSQL / Sqlite and MongoDB. Platform experience including JBoss EAP6, Infinispan/Data Grid, Red Hat Mobile Application Platform. Platform virtualization experience in Xen, KVM, OpenStack, Kubernetes and OpenShift 3/4. Automation experience with Ansible.

While I have a Linux first mentality, my OS experience includes indepth command of RHEL / Debian based systems, Mac OS and Windows.

I'm a passionate learner actively pursuing new technologies, online courses, certifications, etc. Currently maintaining a clearance.

While I work to keep LinkedIn up to date as much as possible, please also reference my interactive resume at https:// www.wardzinski.info.

# Experience

Red Hat

7 years 6 months

Senior Linux Consultant August 2017 - Present (3 years 10 months) McLean. VA

As a Senior Consultant, I'm utilized in a variety of realms where leadership and expertise are necessary. My primary areas of focus are application development heavy in OpenShift / Kubernetes integration. Secondary focus remains solidly in infrastructure and DevOps. I have a deep focus on Linux related technologies and cloud first architecture design. Innate ability to ramp up on technologies where I may not have experience.

Development experience under this role includes Node.js, Angular 8+, Ionic, iOS/Android, Python and a slew of testing frameworks. Infrastructure focus purely on Linux realms with automation experience utilizing Ansible. CI/CD DevOps experience utilizing Jenkins pipelines.

Middleware Consultant

December 2013 - August 2017 (3 years 9 months)

As a middleware consultant, I was responsible for a number of different tasks in a number of different spaces including mobile, Red Hat POC initiatives, integration and acquisitions.

- Mobile: Large team development of front-end and back-end applications using Node.js, Angular, Cordova (and others) utilizing mobile development best practices.
- POC: Lead POC initiative for JBoss Data Grid Infrastructure implementation. Assisted with implementation, configuration, tuning, and performance testing of a Infinispan/DataGrid caching solution replicated across multiple nodes using parallel hydration and daisy chaining techniques.
- Integration: Designed, configured and set down best practices for maintenance of large clusters of physical and virtual Linux based machines for Hadoop. Lead the team through complex Linux problems, systems automation in Bash and Puppet.
- Acquisitions: Assessed the technological health of multiple companies. Provided technical analysis through a deep dive of the application code, architecture, etc.

Grayson Digital, LLC Small Business Owner January 2005 - Present (16 years 5 months) Manassas, VA Since 2005, Grayson Digital has been a specialist in full-stack development projects. From small to large businesses we've provided: simple to complex frontend and backend solutions, a range of hosting solutions including highly available implementations, systems development (Linux & Windows), mobile development & microservices.

Website: https://www.grayson.digital

Progeny Systems
Software / System Engineer
November 2006 - November 2013 (7 years 1 month)
Manassas, VA

Software and Systems Engineering integration expertise is what I strived for here. Headed up virtualization research in open source virtualization technologies such as Xen, KVM, and opensource portions of Citrix. Researched and employed various cloud based virtualization toolstacks such as OpenStack. Developed and maintained software and systems level projects in support of U.S. Naval technical efforts. Engineered and implemented custom Linux server farms. Researched new & emerging technologies.

Primary languages used: Java, C++, XML, Bash.

Technologies: RHEL and Debian based Linux, Virtualization (Xen, KVM, etc).

ServiceLink, LP
Tier 2 Product Support / App Developer
May 2006 - November 2006 (7 months)
Imperial, PA

As a Tier 2 product support contractor, I provided escalated technical product support to a variety of products housed under ServiceLink, Inc. I was tasked to fix users problems as they come up in software, routinely make database edits (T-SQL) as well as code debugging (VB6, C#, and .NET) to keep products running smoothly and without error and develop C# tools to automate many complicated processes within the company/system.

University of Pittsburgh School of Nursing Web App / DB Developer November 2004 - May 2006 (1 year 7 months) Pittsburgh, PA Wrote technical hardware specifications and procurement suggestions in project planning that resulted in a successful project startup of the e-QLTP (Electronic Questionnaire for Lung Transplant Patients). Designed, developed, and implemented electronic survey functionality in Microsoft Access to improve survey methods for attaining metrics associated with lung transplant patients. Developed additional online versions in PHP, MySQL and JavaScript to enable medical surveys to be completed away from the clinical setting. Worked closely with research team to optimize database efficiency and to attain research team's standards and expectations.

invivodata
QA / Web Developer
November 2003 - November 2005 (2 years 1 month)
Pittsburgh, PA

Lead major revisions of company training database. Developed initial version in MS Access to statically track employees as they submitted training (in paper form). Developed and released subsequent versions in PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript to enable dynamic tracking without QA intervention. Developed and released an administration website to ease knowledge required by QA to effectively administer to the online training website. Developed web applications under regulations such as HIPAA, Part11, etc.

## Education

University of Pittsburgh

Bachelors, Information Sciences, Computer Science · (2001 - 2006)